{
    "id": "2b669c99c55e4f1b8a468dd96ec03879",
    "title": "Types Of Sentences",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The boys drew lots to determine who would get to play first.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The loss of her purse caused her much inconvenience.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one subject and one predicate.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He is lonely because his wife is out of town this weekend.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Art lovers flocked to the gallery opening.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one subject and one predicate.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He decided to wind up his business and start fresh.",
            "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Many people feel listless on rainy days.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one subject and one predicate.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He is from a family of illustrious lineage.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one subject and one predicate.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He became rich through wise investments.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one subject and one predicate.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "A howl of protest went up when the voting was announced.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple past",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The helicopter hovered over the house.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one subject and one predicate.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I donâ€™t know what I should do now.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "This is very heady punch, so watch your step.",
            "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}